Ricketts mss. III, 1856-1979 LMC 1831
Lilly Library
- The Scriptorium
  - Certificates and Diplomas
    - Specimens, 1892-1969
      - Alliance Life Insurance Company, 1948 (Box 47)
      - American Academy of Art, 1946-1951 (Box 47)
      - American Conservatory of Music, 1930-1944 (Box 47)
      - American Extension School of Law, 1928-1934 (Box 47)
      - American Real Estate Institute, 1926 (Box 47)
      - Anna Morgan School of Expression, 20th century (Box 47)
      - Armour Institute - Department of Library Science, 1890s (Box 47)
      - Armour Institute of Technology, 1933 (Box 47)
      - Barrington Country Day School, 1939 (Box 47)
      - Battle Creek College, 1890s (Box 47)
      - The Bell School, 1940-1941 (Box 47)
      - Bensenville Community High School, 1941 (Box 47)
      - Bethel Theological Seminary, 1927-1930 (Box 47)
      - Boston High School, 1890s (Box 47)
      - Chicago Central Station Institute, undated (Box 47)
      - Chicago Institute, Academic and Pedagogic, undated (Box 47)
      - Chicago Kent College of Law, 1898-1930 (Box 47)
      - Chicago Normal College, 1931 (Box 47)
      - Chicago Public Schools - Grammar Department, 1905 (Box 47)
      - Chicago Public Schools - High School, 1892-1919 (Box 47)
      - Chicago Public Schools - Vocational course, 1919-1931 (Box 47)
      - Chicago Public Schools - Teachers' certificate, 20th century (Box 47)
      - Chicago Public Schools - Technical Junior College, 20th century (Box 47)
      - The Clara L. Joyce School of Piano Music, 20th century (Box 47)
      - Cleveland Kindergarten Primary Training School, 1923 (Box 47)
      - Collegiate Institute, 1890s (Box 47)
      - Columbia School of Music, 1927-1929 (Box 47)
      - Conservatory of Music, Hastings, Nebraska, 1930s (Box 47)
      - Cook County Hospital, 20th century (Box 47)
      - Dundee Community High School, 1940-1941 (Box 47)
      - Drexel Conservatory of Music, undated (Box 47)
      - Elgin High School, 20th century (Box 47)
      - Elm Place Intermediate School, 1920-1940 (Box 47)
      - Elmhurst College, 1940-1961 (Box 47)
      - Elsabeth Port School, Wheeling, Illinois, 20th century (Box 47)
      - National College of Education and Demonstration School, 1929-1936 (Box 53)
      - National Institute for Commercial and Trade Organization Executives, 1944-1950 (Box 53)
      - New Trier Township High School, 1940-1948 (Box 53)
      - North Dakota - State Normal School, undated (Box 53)
      - Northwestern University, 1919-1940 (Box 53)
      - Passavant Evanston/Memorial Hospital School of Nursing, 1932-1935 (Box 53)
      - Post Graduate Hospital/Medical School of Chicago, 1890s (Box 53)
      - Presbyterian Theological Seminary of Chicago, undated (Box 53)
      - Purdue University, 1932-1937 (Box 53)
      - R. R. Donnelley and Sons, Co., 1916-1927 (Box 53)
      - Rockford College, 1940-1944 (Box 53)
      - Rush Medical College, 1902-1923 (Box 53)
      - St. Bernard's Hotel Dieu Hospital, 1940 (Box 53)
      - Saint Paul's Theological Seminary, 1941 (Box 53)
      - South Dakota - State Normal School, undated (Box 53)
      - Spartan Academy, Landrum, South Carolina, 1900s (Box 53)
      - Spaulding Graded School, Barre, Vermont, undated (Box 53)
      - Stanley Hall, Minneapolis, 1890-1904 (Box 53)
      - Stevan School, 1900s (Box 53)
      - The Swedish Baptist Theological Seminary, 1900s (Box 53)
      - Tomlins School of Music, 1900s (Box 53)
      - The United States Food Administration - Service Award, 1917-1918 (Box 53)
      - The University of Chicago, including the University High School, 1896-1932 (Box 53)
      - University of Illinois, 1932-1934 (Box 53)
      - Valparaiso University, undated (Box 53)
      - Virginia Union University, 1948-1949 (Box 53)
      - Wesley College, Grand Forks, North Dakota, 1930-1932 (Box 53)
      - Western Military Academy, 1927-1969 (Box 53)
    - Specimen set A-L (I missing) (Box 47)
    - Design materials - blank specimens (full size) (Box 47)
    - Fraternity certificates - A-Z (Box 50)
    - Fraternity certificates - Beta Theta Pi (Box 50)
  - Commercial designs - Baldwin Company, undated (Box 19, Folder 41)
  - Darrow, Clarence S. - A Persian Pearl and Other Essays
    Published by C. L. Ricketts, Chicago, 1902
    - Advertisements and notices, 1902-1929 (Box 19, Folder 42)
      Includes typed copy for an advertisement and printed material
    - Correspondence and papers, 1900-1967 (Box 19, Folder 43)
      Letters concerning orders and production. Includes an order to McClurg's for a copy of the Roycroft edition of A Persian Pearl, Aug. 30, 1900; printing costs at R. R. Donnelly's, May 23, 1902; list of prices received for A Persian Pearl, 1902-1904. Among the correspondents are: Clarence Seward Darrow, 1857-1938; Karl Knortz, 1841-1918; Harvey Porter Layton; Benedict Prieth, 1870?-1934, editor of The Whim; Alonzo Rice, 1867-1946, John Spargo, 1876-1966; Edwin C. Walker, ?-1931
  - Designs - Clasps and corners (Box 19, Folder 44)
  - Designs - Monograms, 8 Folders (Box 19, Folder 45-52)
  - Designs - Tracing paper (Box 36)
    Tracing paper copies of signatures, figures, scenes, initials, etc. for reproducing on the several works of the Scriptorium
  - Designs - Initials (Box 36)
    In pen, pencil, hand colored, proofs, and photocopy
  - Emblems and seals (Box 19, Folder 54)
  - Memorials, Resolutions, and Testimonials
    The materials comprise an incomplete assortment of drafts - holograph, typed, and printed, photographs of finished leaves, illuminated work, bound volumes, job records, and clippings
    - Young, Otto, 1908 (Box 24, Folder 218)
    - Youngker, Charles F., 1978 (Box 24, Folder 219)
    - Zeese, Alexander, 1899 (Box 24, Folder 220)
    - Zettler, F. T., 1916 (Box 24, Folder 221)
    - Zuppke, Robert C., 1937 (Box 24, Folder 222)
    - Biester, Fred C., 1943 (Box 45)
    - Coffee, Lenore and Cowen, William Joyce, 1940 (Box 45)
    - Disney, Walt, 1949 (Box 45)
    - Gage, Lyman Judson, 1891 (Box 45)
    - Insull, Samuel, 1930 (Box 45)
    - McLeish, Andrew, 1927 (Box 45)
    - Pius XII, 1946 (Box 45)
    - Potter, Andrey Abraham, 1946 (Box 45)
    - Roach, H. David, undated (Box 45)
    - Harrison, Carter H., 1893 (Box 45)
    - Eisenhower, Dwight David, 1947 (Box 45)
    - Radford, Arthur William, 1954 (Box 48)
    - Randall, Emily and Clarence, undated (Box 48)
    - Reeve, Harold, 1953 (Box 48)
    - Resch, Robert P., 1954 (Box 48)
    - Richardson, Charles C., 1916 (Box 48)
    - Robinson, Jessie King, 1958 (Box 48)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, 1942 (Box 48)
    - Rose, Terry, 1953 (Box 48)
    - Rotary Club, Highland Park, Illinois, 1951 (Box 48)
    - Ruhm, John Jr., 1944 (Box 48)
    - Rutherford, James, 1959 (Box 48)
    - Sacks, Louis L., 1904 (Box 48)
    - Safford, George B., 1908 (Box 48)
    - St. Louis Master Bakers Protective and Benevolent Association, 1936 (Box 48)
    - Sarnoff, David S., 1952 (Box 48)
    - Scribner, Gilbert Hilton, 1952 (Box 48)
    - Sears Mail Order, Department 939, 1953 (Box 48)
    - Shropshire, Kenneth, 1949 (Box 48)
    - Simonds, Mrs. James P., 1956 (Box 48)
    - Slichter, Donald S., 1961 (Box 48)
    - Sloan, Alfred E., 1937 (Box 48)
    - Slocum, Herman C., 1957 (Box 48)
    - Smith, Clarence D., 1954 (Box 48)
    - Smith, Horace Greeley, 1953-1955 (Box 48)
    - Smith, Solomon Albert, 1949 (Box 48)
    - Somerset, Lady Henry, 1892 (Box 48)
    - Spoor, John Alden, 1926-1927 (Box 48)
    - Stockton, Joseph D., 1957 (Box 48)
    - Stoker Manufacturers Association - Member Certificate, 20th century (Box 48)
    - Stolp, Rufus Byron, 1942 (Box 48)
    - Stritch, Samuel Cardinal, 1952 (Box 48)
    - Stults, Allen P., 1966 (Box 48)
    - Sullivan, Daniel Arthur, 1964 (Box 48)
    - Sutherland, Eugene, 1946 (Box 48)
    - Swift, Harold H., 1955 (Box 48)
    - Falk, Louis, 1896 (Box 48)
    - Farwell, Loring C., 1966 (Box 48)
    - The Ford Foundation, 1956 (Box 48)
    - Forvis, Harry, 1888 (Box 48)
    - Frautschi, Walter A., 1957 (Box 48)
    - Frick, Ford C., 1955 (Box 48)
    - Frisch, Sidney, 1953 (Box 48)
    - Gage, Lyman Judson, 1897-1927 (Box 48)
    - Gahan, Thomas, 1893 (Box 48)
    - Gardner, George, 1959 (Box 48)
    - Garrett Biblical/Theological Seminary, 1940-1960 (Box 48)
    - Gieger, C. Harve, 1956 (Box 48)
    - Gilkey, Charles W., 1947 (Box 48)
    - Gillam, Lawrence G., 1961 (Box 48)
    - Grochowskiemu, Leonowi, 1946 (Box 48)
    - Gustav V, King of Sweden, 1950 (Box 48)
    - Halperin, Carl, 1948 (Box 48)
    - Hamilton, John B., undated (Box 48)
    - Hamm, Pete, Jr., 1953 (Box 48)
    - Harrah, William F., 1946-1956 (Box 48)
    - Harris, Albert Wadsworth, 1947-1958 (Box 48)
    - Harris, Harriet Meikle, undated (Box 48)
    - Harris, Harv and Fran, 1950 (Box 48)
    - Harrison, Harry, 1958 (Box 48)
    - Harrison, Will J., undated (Box 48)
    - Hart, William Lee, 1929 (Box 48)
    - Hartnett, George Francis and Marianne Deuses, 1956 (Box 48)
    - Harvard Community Memorial Hospital - Book of Memorials and Gifts, 1956 (Box 48)
    - Haskell, Clinton H., 1952 (Box 48)
    - Heinz, Vira Ingham, 1945 (Box 48)
    - Henry, Nell R., 1941 (Box 48)
    - Hogness, Thorfin Rustin, 1947 (Box 48)
    - Hoover, Herbert, 1926-1950 (Box 48)
    - Horton, Horace Babcock, 1957 (Box 48)
    - Huron College, South Dakota, 1926-1938 (Box 48)
    - Hyman, Sigmund, 1889 (Box 48)
    - Illinois College, 1946 (Box 48)
    - Illinois State Dental Society, 1964 (Box 48)
    - Illinois Supreme Court, 1931 (Box 48)
    - Independent Schools Association Service Awards, 1960 (Box 48)
    - Indiana State Dental Association, 1958 (Box 48)
    - Industrial Relations Counselors, Inc., 1951 (Box 48)
    - Ingram, William B., 1952 (Box 48)
    - International Sunday School Association - Life Member, 1920s (Box 48)
    - Jacoby, Neil H., 1959 (Box 48)
    - Junge, August C., 1956 (Box 48)
    - Karker, Maurice H., 1948-1952 (Box 48)
    - Kelleher, Michael T., 1958 (Box 48)
    - Kenwood-Plymouth Church Endowment Fund, undated (Box 48)
    - Kiley, John P., 1957 (Box 48)
    - Kimberley, James, 1958 (Box 48)
    - Kingery, Robert, 1939 (Box 48)
    - Kingham, James J., 1958 (Box 48)
    - Kline, Allan B., 1954 (Box 48)
    - Klutznick, Philip M., 1966 (Box 48)
    - Kmet, William Emil, 1964 (Box 48)
    - Kopack, Frank R., 1961 (Box 48)
    - Kraft, James Lewis, undated (Box 48)
    - Kresge, Stanley Sebastian, 1959 (Box 48)
    - Kropp, Gustav Alfred, undated (Box 48)
    - Krueger, Karl K., 1957 (Box 48)
    - Laas, Robert M., 1960 (Box 48)
    - Lake Forest University, 1945 (Box 48)
    - Lake Geneva Yacht Club Honor Roll, 1945 (Box 48)
    - Lawless, Theodore R., 1950-1957 (Box 48)
    - Laws, Curtis Lee, 1908 (Box 48)
    - Leinemann, A. A., 1961 (Box 48)
    - Lindermann, Albert T., undated (Box 48)
    - Logan, John A., 1953 (Box 48)
    - Love, Paul, 1958 (Box 48)
    - Loyola University - Chicago - Society of Jesus, 1941 (Box 48)
    - Taylor, Graham, 1937 (Box 49)
    - Truax, A. Harold, 1959 (Box 49)
    - Twombly, Thomas B., 1890 (Box 49)
    - UARCO, 1952-1968 (Box 49)
    - Underwood, Gladys, 1957 (Box 49)
    - United Air Lines, undated (Box 49)
    - University of Chicago Alumni, 1954-1960 (Box 49)
    - University of Wisconsin, 1904 (Box 49)
    - Upton, Louis C., 1949 (Box 49)
    - Valentine, John, 1949 (Box 49)
    - Van der Vries, Bernice T., 1956 (Box 49)
    - Vennard, Edward, 1966 (Box 49)
    - Victor Talking Machine Co., 1912 (Box 49)
    - Wahl, Elizabeth B., 1946 (Box 49)
    - Waldorf Paper Products Co., 1955 (Box 49)
    - Walker, Randolph Clark, 1959 (Box 49)
    - Watson, Thomas John, 1947 (Box 49)
    - Watson, William Joseph, 1926 (Box 49)
    - Webster, James, 1910 (Box 49)
    - Weed, Randolph Woodruff, 1956 (Box 49)
    - Wentworth, Frank W., 1931 (Box 49)
    - Wesley Memorial Hospital, 1951 (Box 49)
    - Whalen, William J., 1948 (Box 49)
    - Wieder, Alexander C., 1951 (Box 49)
    - Wilford, George Ernest, 1947 (Box 49)
    - Willard, Frances E., 1889 (Box 49)
    - Williams, Roger F., 1944 (Box 49)
    - WNBQ-NBC, 1951 (Box 49)
    - Wood, Robert E., 1959 (Box 49)
    - World's Sunday School Association - Membership Certificate, 1904 (Box 49)
    - Wyles, Tom R., 1952 (Box 49)
    - W., Robert "Bob" P., 1956 (Box 49)
    - Yager, Vincent, 1957 (Box 49)
    - Young Men's Jewish Council, 1943-1953 (Box 49)
    - McCall, John A., 1894 (Box 49)
    - McCloud, Bently G., 1943 (Box 49)
    - McCormick, Robert R., undated (Box 49)
    - McEnery, W. B., 1893 (Box 49)
    - McFaul, James A., 1898 (Box 49)
    - McKay, John T. R., 1890 (Box 49)
    - McLeish, Andrew, 1927 (Box 49)
    - Magin, Fritz, 1956 (Box 49)
    - Main, Gordon, 1957 (Box 49)
    - Mann, Michael, 1952 (Box 49)
    - Massmann, Frederick Henry, 1934 (Box 49)
    - Medina, Harold R., 1951 (Box 49)
    - Methodist Church - Board of Hospitals and Homes Award, undated (Box 49)
    - Methodist Home for Children, 1951 (Box 49)
    - Metropolitan Lodge, No. 860 - F. & A.M., 1917 (Box 49)
    - Meyer, Max Karl, 1937 (Box 49)
    - Michelson, Albert A., 1907 (Box 49)
    - Molezzi, Emily Rosalie and Charles Robert Sak, 1959 (Box 49)
    - Motley, Arthur, 1950 (Box 49)
    - Mrozka, Stanislawa, 1950 (Box 49)
    - Muldoon, Kenneth, 1959 (Box 49)
    - Mundelein, George Cardinal, undated (Box 49)
    - National Association of Real Estate Boards - Member Certificate, 1927-1930 (Box 49)
    - Nelson, Ralph, 1958 (Box 49)
    - Nelson, Richard H., 1956 (Box 49)
    - Nettelhorst, Louis, 1893 (Box 49)
    - Newell, John, 1894 (Box 49)
    - Newman-Rudolph Lithographing Co., 1946 (Box 49)
    - Nobel, Alfred, 1907 (Box 49)
    - Noyes, La Verne, 1919 (Box 49)
    - O'Brien, Peter, 1937 (Box 49)
    - O'Brien, Raymond J., 1953 (Box 49)
    - Omaha Brokerage Co., 1949 (Box 49)
    - Order of Saint Philip - Citation, 1942 (Box 49)
    - Perkins, George W., 1894 (Box 49)
    - Perkins Products Company, 1950 (Box 49)
    - Pierce, John Bartlett, 1917 (Box 49)
    - Pillsbury, John S., 1889 (Box 49)
    - Pisinger, Joseph, 1954 (Box 49)
    - Plee-zing Company - Recognition Certificate, 1940 (Box 49)
    - Potter, Andrey Abraham, 1963 (Box 49)
    - Prior, Frank O., 1957 (Box 49)
    - Quill and Scroll Award, 1930 (Box 49)
    - Alvin, Walter C., 1955 (Box 52)
    - American Association of Industrial Physicians and Surgoeons, undated (Box 52)
    - American Bandmasters Association, undated (Box 52)
    - American College of Surgeons, 1915 (Box 52)
    - American Dental Trade Association, 1939-1950 (Box 52)
    - American Farm Bureau Federation, 1922-1955 (Box 52)
    - Armstrong, Frank Hough, 1920 (Box 52)
    - Baer, Arthur and Alice, 1958 (Box 52)
    - Bahn, Bertram I., 1955 (Box 52)
    - Baker, W. R. G., 1955 (Box 52)
    - Bee, Joseph, 1893 (Box 52)
    - Behr, Louis, 1947 (Box 52)
    - Best, Louis J., 1961 (Box 52)
    - Blackett, Hill, 1962 (Box 52)
    - Block, Philip D., 1917-1942 (Box 52)
    - Bourn, Leslie, 1951 (Box 52)
    - Brace, James A., 1890 (Box 52)
    - Bradley Mining Co., 1951 (Box 52)
    - Brenan, Thomas, 1904 (Box 52)
    - Brennan, Michael, 1894 (Box 52)
    - Brown, Mark Anthony, 1955-1962 (Box 52)
    - Brown, Wesley E., 1966 (Box 52)
    - Browning, L. A., 1951 (Box 52)
    - Brun, Francois-Julien, 1953 (Box 52)
    - Budd, Ralph, 1958 (Box 52)
    - Burgess-Norton Pool, 1945 (Box 52)
    - Burns, Arthur F., 1958 (Box 52)
    - Byerly, George L., 1950 (Box 52)
    - Carthage, Indiana - Mill of Container Corporation of America, 1948 (Box 52)
    - Cass, Herbert Herman, 1955 (Box 52)
    - Cella, David L., 1957 (Box 52)
    - Central Baptist Orphanage, undated (Box 52)
    - A Century of Progress International Exposition of 1933 and 1934, undated (Box 52)
    - Charlotte, Grand Duchess of Luxemburg, 1962 (Box 52)
    - Chicago - Board of Trade, 1948 (Box 52)
    - Chicago - Honored Dead of 1914-1918, undated (Box 52)
    - Chicago White Sox, 1952 (Box 52)
    - Chicago World's Fair Centennial Celebration of 1933, 1928 (Box 52)
    - Cisler, Walker Leo, 1967 (Box 52)
    - Clark, Sheldon, 1951-1952 (Box 52)
    - Clarke, Philip R., 1966 (Box 52)
    - The Cliff-Dwellers, undated (Box 52)
    - College of New Jersey, 1896 (Box 52)
    - Colon de la Cerda, Cristoval, Duke of Veragua, 1893 (Box 52)
    - Comiskey, Charles A., undated (Box 52)
    - Compton, Arthur H., 1952 (Box 52)
    - Cordiner, Ralph T., 1961 (Box 52)
    - Crerar, John, 1889-1890 (Box 52)
    - Cummings, Nathan, 1956 (Box 52)
    - Daniels, John J., 1953 (Box 52)
    - Dauber, Fred A., 1952 (Box 52)
    - Davies, Rees, 1953 (Box 52)
    - Davis, Charles H., 1965 (Box 52)
    - Davis, Lloyd, 1963 (Box 52)
    - Deering, The C. Printing Co., 1951 (Box 52)
    - Deering, William, 1896-1907 (Box 52)
    - Detroit Real Estate Board, 1925 (Box 52)
    - Dobrick, August C., 1961 (Box 52)
    - Dubor, Charles H., 1918 (Box 52)
    - Duke Pediatric Society, 1954 (Box 52)
    - Duncan, Nicholas, undated (Box 52)
    - Durbahn, Walt, 1951 (Box 52)
    - Dyche, William A., 1936-1938 (Box 52)
    - Edison, Thomas A., 1931 (Box 52)
    - Edison, Thomas A.; Carl H. Wilson; William E. Gilmore; and Frank K. Dolbeer, 1906 (Box 52)
    - Elliott, Ben George, 1966 (Box 52)
    - Elliott, Frank Rumsey, 1961 (Box 52)
    - Emery, James A., undated (Box 52)
    - Evanston Hospital, 1940 (Box 52)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 20)
    - A. B. Dick Company, 1965 (Box 20)
    - Abt, Isaac Arthur, 1947 (Box 20)
    - Adams, Frances, 1967 (Box 20)
    - Adams, Harry Wilfred, 1952 (Box 20)
    - Adams, Roger, 1950 (Box 20)
    - Aleman Valdes, Miguel, 1956 (Box 20)
    - Allen, Harvey S., 1941 (Box 20)
  - The Panels, Illuminated
    - Materials about illuminated panels (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Illuminated historical materials (folder 1) (Box 41)
    - Illuminated historical materials (folder 2) (Map case 1)
  - Poems (Box 25, Folder 33)
    Poems collected as source material for work by The Scriptorium
  - Poems and prose (folder 1) (Box 25, Folder 34)
    Work prepared by The Scriptorium [fill in from binder]
  - Poems and prose (folder 2) (Box 51)
  - Prose (mottoes, maxims, etc.), A-Z (Box 25, Folder 37)
    Holograph and typed copies, perhaps collected as source material for work by The Scriptorium
  - Prose (mottoes, maxims, etc.), contributed by George Iles (Box 25, Folder 38)
  - Materials memoranda (Box 25, Folder 39)
  - Materials memoranda - the making of brass tools, Arthur Hertzberg (Box 25, Folder 40)
  - Materials memoranda - the making of brass tools, Paul Kummer (Box 25, Folder 41)
  - Realia
    - Box of silver foil from George M. Whiley, London; box of Dennisons Notarial Seals, gold-colored (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Ink and tools (Box 44)
    - Type and metal blocks (Box 44)
  - Specimens of work
    - Albums, 2 Folders (Box 26, Folder 2-3)
      Three albums of black and white photographs for presenting the nature of the work performed at The Scriptorium
    - Style examples (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Six "hands" inscribed in Scriptorium, 1950 (Box 36)
    - Summary statement of the nature of work done at The Scriptorium (3 copies), ca. 1960 (Box 36)
    - Examples of engraved work and photocopies of illuminated work (Box 38)
    - Drovers Deposit National Bank of Chicago, July 14th, 1910 (Box 54)
    - Chicago City Railway Company, July 14th, 1910 (Box 54)
    - Mercury - Tribute to "possesor of this Scroll," by Jupiter, O.M., and Charles A. Nicoll, 1929? (Box 56)
    - Beta Theta Pi, University of Illinois - Sigma Rho Chapter Achievement, 1 September 1932 (Box 55)
    - In Honor of Harold Manasse (Box 57)
  - Debentures, mortgages (Box 26, Folder 20)
    Engravings by CLR [lb] 1) Des Moines Loan and Trust Co. 2) Lake Geneva Water and Light Co.
  - For club officers (Box 26, Folder 23)
    Clippings giving names of organization officials who may require resolutions
  - For diplomas (Box 26, Folder 24)
    Clippings regarding names of graduates for whom diplomas may be prepared
  - For resolutions (honorary) (Box 26, Folder 25)
    Clippings regarding the engraving of resolutions for living individuals, some of which may have been engrossed and illuminated by CLR
  - For resolutions (obituaries) (Box 26, Folder 26)
    Clippings regarding the preparation of resolutions upon the death of individuals
  - Poems, A-K (Box 26, Folder 38)
    Collected ideas for Scriptorium work. Some of the poems are clippings from poet researcher Louella D. Everett of Boston
  - Poems, L-Z (Box 26, Folder 39)
  - Prose (mottoes, maxims, etc) - clippings (Box 27, Folder 1)
    Clippings collected for ideas
  - Prose (mottoes, maxims, etc) - leaflets and pamphlets (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - "Desiderata" (Box 27, Folder 9)
    With occasional additions in pencil in the hand of C. L. Ricketts
  - Golden Anniversary, 1885-1935
    Materials prepared for the 30th anniversary of The Scriptorium
    - Booklet, 1935 (Box 27, Folder 27)
      Prepared in honor of CLR and The Scriptorium. With a Christmas greeting card from Julia and Jasper
    - Text, 1935 (Box 27, Folder 28)
      Text to precede compilation of congratulatory letters from friends to honor CLR
    - Illuminated volume, 1935 (Box 54)
      Bound and illuminated volume of congratulatory correspondence in red box
    - Journal of Work Performances for The Scriptorium, 1918-1919 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - The Scriptorium of C. L. Ricketts (Box 28, Folder 39)
    Author unknown
  - Photos of clients for miniatures by the Scriptorium (Box 39)
  - Sample folders and enclosures (Box 42, Box 43)
  - Blank paper and vellum samples (Box 43)
- Subject Files
  - Bookplates by others (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Book and Periodical cover designs (Box 53)
  - Bindings, 2 Folders (Box 40)
  - Calendars - Ibbs, Edith A., The Shelley Calendar (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Calendars - unidentified (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Calligraphy - Firms and schools (Box 37)
  - Calligraphy - Specimens (Box 37)
  - Calling cards - designs (Box 18, Folder 19)
    Elaborate designs only with names not filled in. Designer unknown
  - Calling cards - England, Europe, Japan (Box 18, Folder 20)
    About 120 cards. Rarely with messages [lb] Includes John Masefield
  - Calling cards - USA (Box 18, Folder 21)
    About 191 cards. Rarely with messages
  - Cases (Box 40)
  - Drawings (unidentified) (Box 19, Folder 53)
  - Empty Envelopes
    - 1882-1911 (Box 19, Folder 55)
    - 1912-1978 (Box 19, Folder 56)
    - Undated - A-Z (Box 19, Folder 57)
    - Undated - to CLR (Box 19, Folder 58)
  - Examples of engraved/illuminated work from other scriptoria (principally Vinycomb) (Box 38)
  - Grolier Club, 1918-1920 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    Programs and envelopes
  - Periodicals (Box 37)
  - Pictures
    - Airplanes (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Austria (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Bank Office Interior (Box 25, Folder 10)
      By CLR
    - Belgium (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Buildings, Unidentified (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Chester, England (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Cities - U.S. (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Czechoslovakia (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - England (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Europe (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - France (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Fruit (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Germany (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Ireland (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - Ireland, England, Scotland (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - Ireland, England, Scotland, France, Belgium, Germany, Switzerland (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - Italy (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Miscellaneous postcard views and greetings (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - Netherlands, 2 Folders (Box 25, Folder 26-27)
    - Object, unidentified (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - Railroads (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - Switzerland, 2 Folders (Box 25, Folder 30-31)
    - United States (Box 25, Folder 32)
    - Oversize (Box 36)
  - Portraits, A-Z (folder 1) (Box 25, Folder 35)
  - Portraits, unidentified (Box 25, Folder 36)